# **JASON WEST**

# Madison Heights, MI 48071 248.854.2130 jasonlwest@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/iasonlwest/ | GitHub: https://qithub.com/ilw429

Portfolio: jasonlwest.com

#### SUMMARY:

Full stack web professional coming from a background in the fast-paced retail industry with extensive experience in team building, managing people and processes. Understands the full stack of a web application including working with API's. Aware of the Scrum and Agile methodology, highly skilled at communicating, delegating, as well as praising and holding people accountable. Considered to be relentless at delivering assignments on time, a quick learner who pays attention to the details and has advanced problem solving abilities.

## TECHNICAL SKILLS:

Languages: React, JavaScript, jQuery, MySQL, MongoDB, Firebase, Node, Express, Handlebars, Angular, CSS,

**HTML** 

Applications: Material UI, Bootstrap, Git, Terminal, JIRA, Bash, VScode

#### Projects:

RambleSpace | Github: <a href="https://github.com/jlw429/RambleSpace">https://github.com/jlw429/RambleSpace</a>

Fully functioning front and back end (including authentication) social media website resembling Twitter.

Technologies used: React, Redux, JavaScript, Firebase

Blog | Github: https://github.com/jlw429/JasonsBlog

A full-stack blog built with React, node.js, express and MySql. Simple blog with the ability to follow the crud operators of create, read, and delete.

**Gradebook** | GitHub: <a href="https://github.com/jlw429/Project2">https://github.com/jlw429/Project2</a> Website: <a href="https://msu-project-two.herokuapp.com/">https://msu-project-two.herokuapp.com/</a> Full-stack web project as a way for the administrators in a school to give up-to-date attendance records from all your teachers in real-time. Teachers and student support staff can overview daily attendance records as well as individual student profiles. Technologies used: Javascript, HTML, CSS, node, express, twilio send grid API.

Thats My Jam | GitHub: <a href="https://github.com/jlw429/MusicArtists">https://jlw429.github.io/MusicArtists/#</a>
A way for the user to learn more about an artist they may have heard on TikTok or the radio. It gives a short biography of the artist or band, you also have their top 50 songs and the app has the technology to show the music video from youTube that populates as a modal in the middle of the page. The app was built from scratch using Javascript, Jquery, Bootstrap, CSS, HTML and using APIs from the audio database, last.fm, and youtube.

**Weather Dashboard** | GitHub: <a href="https://github.com/jlw429/HW6Weather">https://jlw429.github.io/HW6Weather</a>/ App was developed for a quick way to type in a city, get the city, current conditions and five day forecast. Utilizing API's from openweathermap as well as Jquery, Javascript, Bootstrap, CSS, and HTML.

# WORK EXPERIENCE:

# The Kroger Company | Store Manager (2016 - 2020)

Rochester, MI

Increased customer satisfaction while bringing strategic direction to my team to help achieve departmental goals. Maintained a positive attitude and presence on the sales floor. Adjusted weekly sales forecasts while accounting for sales trends and seasons. Educated associates on new processes and procedures promoting continuity in the workplace. Responsible for leading multiple deadlines to completion in regards to in-store and district priorities. Hired and terminated team members and processed paperwork while adhering to FMLA, labor, and OSHA requirements.

- Lead daily staff standups where every supervisor briefly reports updates to the team.
- Increased grocery department in-stock rate from 93.82% in November 2018 to 98.81% by May 2019.
- Improved the store's grocery pickup department to be number two in the Michigan Division for customer pick-up time at 5 minutes 47 seconds on average in 2020.

Publix Supermarkets, Inc. | Store Manager (2012 - 2016)

Nashville, TN

**Asst. Store Manager (2008-2012)** 

Nashville, TN

Ensured legal compliance while handling sensitive and confidential information and documents. Resolved conflicts between employees promoting a cohesive team while boosting morale and providing top-notch customer service. Hired and dismissed team members as needed. Designed, tracked, and analyzed store reports. Managed projects while producing positive results. Met corporate goals and forecasted weekly sales.

- Worked on a three month special project re-developing district policies regarding shoplifting. This process lowered unidentified shrink 7% throughout the district.
- Winner of the 2013 Safety Award for the Atlanta division.
- Led and directed a team of 150+ individuals within a supermarket averaging \$700-850K in sales weekly.

### **EDUCATION:**

## Full Stack Certificate | Michigan State University

**East Lansing, MI** 

A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Firebase, Node Js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js & ReactJS.

#### **Bachelor of Science | University of Central Florida**

Orlando, FL

Major in Health Care Administration, Minor in Health Information Management.